<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on Florian Winkelbauer</title><link>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on Florian Winkelbauer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright 2022, Florian Winkelbauer. All rights reserved.</copyright><atom:link href="https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Behavior</title><link>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/behavior/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/behavior/</guid><description>When (Daniel H. Pink) Chapter 1 Timing is not an art, it&amp;rsquo;s a science. Do not go to the hospital in the afternoon. Seriously. Don&amp;rsquo;t. Our cognitive abilities change over the course of a day. Even if we think that &amp;ldquo;this does not apply to us&amp;rdquo;, these forces have a greater impact than we believe. We can split a day into three mood phases:
Peak Through Recovery The order in which we move through these phases depends on our chronotype.</description></item><item><title>Conference Talks</title><link>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/conference-talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/conference-talks/</guid><description>Pilot Decision Management (Clifford Agius) The TDODAR framework:
Time Is it an emergency? Do we have to act quickly? Do we need to and can we make more time? Do we have time for a cup of coffee? Start a stopwatch and make sure you come back to the &amp;ldquo;T&amp;rdquo; to check if things change Diagnosis What do we think happened?
Discuss the symptoms Ask open questions Find some information to tell me this is not XYZ Agree on the issue to be tackled Make it quick and concise, the clock is ticking!</description></item><item><title>Software Development</title><link>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/software-development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/software-development/</guid><description>Decision Logs Create logs that hold the following information:
Problem you are deciding on Involved people What did you choose? Why? Risks? What other things have you considered? Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you choose them? Michael Nygard described his decision log structure in this blog post:
Context: Describe the forces at play Decision: Your response to these forces Status: The decision status (e.g. &amp;ldquo;proposed&amp;rdquo;) Consequences: What happened afterwards? How To Deal With Configuration Rely on useful default configuration which is stored inside the application: e.</description></item><item><title>Systems</title><link>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/systems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/systems/</guid><description>Antifragility (Nassim Nicholas Taleb) An antifragile system benefits from disorder
Have options (instead of obligations) Create a situation with low downside and high upside Create systems with slack Nonlinear events Convex: a smiling graph. More potential upside than downside (positive Black Swan) Concave: a frowning graph. More potential downside than upside (negative Black Swan) You are robust if doubling exposure doubles harm You are fragile if doubling exposure more than doubles harm A single 100 pound stone hurts more than 100 one pound stones Example Traffic is a function, which depends on the amount of cars.</description></item><item><title>Theater</title><link>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/theater/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://florianwinkelbauer.com/notes/theater/</guid><description>Internationale Sommerakademie für Theater Graz:
Clown Theater 2019 Photos Video Clown Theater 2018 Photos Video Musical 2016 Photos Video Musical 2015 Photos Video Musical 2014 Photos Video</description></item></channel></rss>